

Open Networking Solution Engineer at Edgecore Networks

HsinChu City, Taiwan

☑ blog.pichuang.com.tw ☑ inceptioninx@gmail.com ☐ +886936969620

pichuang in phil-huang-09b09895

Phil Huang comes from Taiwan. He works for Edgecore Networks as a solution engineer and be in charge of open networking technicals PoC design, handling and representing it with the worldwide sales teams (including APAC/EMEA/UAE/Greater China team). He is an active engineer and has 7+ years experiences from B.S. on laaS domain knowledge, and also contributes numbers of opensource projects on GitHub. The primary programming languages are Python and Ansible. He has lots of experiences in public community and business presentations, talking about the trend of SDN/NFV and technical details in Taiwan/US/Japan/China; until 2017, he had spoken in 29 presentations. So far, he is working on a project, based on OpenShift infrastructure which needs to integrate with Big Cloud Fabric product from BigSwitch Networks.

#### **SKILLS**

| Open Networking  Master | Linux<br>Master |                  | DevOps<br>Advanced |              |
|-------------------------|-----------------|------------------|--------------------|--------------|
| sdn&nfv netdevops       | ubuntu          | centos archlinux | docker ansible     | python ci/cd |
| solutions integration   |                 |                  | agile iac          |              |
| laaS<br>Advanced        |                 |                  |                    |              |
| vmware proxmox op       | penshift        |                  |                    |              |
| openstack               |                 |                  |                    |              |

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE (2)**

Open Networking Solution Engineer | Edgecore Networks http://www.edge-core.com

July 2016- Current

Proactively scopes Open Networking technical solutions required to address customer requirements, assesses customers' met and unmet needs, and recommends solutions that optimize value for both the client and the firm to make PoC successful

- Technical support and represent for CumulusLinux / Pica8 / BigSwitch / SONiC / CORD solutions
- Secures from customer technical staff commitments needed to ensure a deal's "technical close"
- Provides coaching and professional development to team member associates to enhance their product knowledge, technical acumen,
   and technical skills

**Technical Lead** | Computer Center, CS, National Chiao Tung University https://www.cs.nctu.edu.tw/cchonor/

September 2013- April 2016

- Plan technical roadmap for building new infrastructure
- Lead team member to improve services and develop the new one

#### **VOLUNTEER**

Ambassador Steering Team | Open Networking Foundation https://ambassadors.opennetworking.org/about/ September 2017 - Current

The ONF Ambassadors Program is designed to empower anyone who is passionate and knowledgeable about ONF to promote the ONF's projects like ONOS or CORD in their region and build a strong local community around it. The Ambassador Steering Team is tasked to ensure that the Ambassadors program runs smoothly and that Ambassadors are fully supported.

- Oversee and support ONOS/CORD ambassador activities
- Represent ONF's projects and teach
- Serve as advisors in strategic decision-making at the organizational level

▼ Co-Founder | SDNDS-TW

August 2014 - Current

https://www.facebook.com/groups/sdnds.tw/

SDN Developer Society (SDNDS-TW) is a local SDN developer community at Taiwan. The main purpose is to create an opportunity for SDN developers to communicate with each other. Everyone can share any information about SDN in the community.

- Promote Open Networking concept locally
- Support and cooperate with others communities (e.g. CNCF, OpenStack, DevOps, Agile)
- Organize SDN/NFV meetup at Taiwan

# EDUCATION (2)

Master of Science Computer Science | National Chiao Tung University

software defined networking | system&network architecture

Bachelor of Science Computer Science | Tunghai University

cyber security | high performance computing | system administrator

# PUBLICATIONS

Distributed OpenNet: A Distributed Software-Defined and Wireless LAN Network Emulator in National Chiao Tung University

1 April 2016

Publish and program an emulator for Software-Defined Wireless Local Area Network and Software-Defined LTE Backhaul Network. The technical knowledges are includes linux network namespace, Mininet framework from ONF and automation for multiple nodes deployment using Ansible

SDN-Based BGP Implementation in Industrial Technology Research Institute

1 September 2016

Viewed a network controlled by an SDN controller (e.g. ONOS) or a cluster of SDN controller as an autonomous system, and use BGP to interact with the rest of the Internet, in order to achieve the effect of both the traditional network and SDN network can be connected. The PoC demonstration with ONF staffs is during Open Networking Summit 2016 event

# LANGUAGES

Mandarin
Native speaker
Intermediate

# INTERESTS

Traveling backpacking openmind

# Reading